嗨,大家好,歡迎收聽《長庚你說》,我是代辦小編 Jojo。
那這一集呢,我們主要是要錄長庚的語文中心,
要帶你了解我們長庚大學語文中心到底在做什麼,
還有什麼樣的資源呢,可以供大家利用。
Hello, teacher Greg, nice to see you.
Hey, great to be here.
Ok, first, we are honored to invite this special guest to participate in the project.
And we also appreciate that you are willing to share your teaching experience
and the information about CGU Language Center with the audience.
So, can you please give us a brief introduction of yourself?
Yeah, sure, I come from Buffalo, New York, in Chinese that's Shui Niu Cun.
I went to university in New York City at Brooklyn College.
I got my master's degree at University of Alaska.
You know, that's a cold place, Alaska.
Yeah, pretty.
And then I came to Taiwan, and I got my PhD in eco-criticism.
That's like a kind of, in a nutshell, that means like looking for green
or environmental readings in literary texts.
And I extended that to anthropology for my research,
which I did in Northeastern Cambodia.
And I've been working at Chang'an University since 2007, from 2007 to 2017.
I took a short break where I brought my family back to the United States.
And then I was very happy to come back to Chang'an in 2020.
And I've been here since and hopefully until Tiangong calls me.
Ok, then it's time for our Q&A.
Here's our first question.
What kind of teaching resources does Chang'an Language Center provide for students?
We have several.
On every Tuesday and Thursday night, we have English Conversation Club.
On Tuesdays, that's done by Teacher Timothy.
And on Thursdays, I do that.
I think we use a similar approach.
Basically, it's held for 12 weeks throughout the semester.
I think weeks 4 through 16.
And we come up with a certain topic every week.
And then we make a list of discussion questions.
And we have a line group for that.
And so we post the questions in advance,
so students can read through them and see if this topic interests them.
And then if they are interested,
they can familiarize themselves with the questions.
And then once the group actually meets,
we have a little introduction.
And then we pair people off into groups of two or three.
And then Timothy and I will filter around to each group
for about five, six minutes a piece
to listen to students' pronunciation.
Try to correct their pronunciation,
add vocabulary where needed,
and just kind of join in on the fun.
It's a very relaxed and kind of informal,
yet structured way to get extra English practice.
And that's every Tuesday and Thursday nights
from 6 p.m. until 7.30 p.m.
And then on Tuesday and Thursdays
from 1 o'clock until 3 o'clock,
we have the English Writing Center.
And on Tuesdays,Teacher David does that,
and on Thursday, it's me.
And the way that goes is,
and this is open to Chang'an students,
research assistants, Chang'an teachers, faculty,
anyone at Chang'an University can come and use this service.
And what you do is you bring us
an English document you have,
whether it's a statement of purpose,
an essay from one of your classes,
or any kind of English document,
and we will read through it with you.
Like the process kind of goes like this.
We try not to make it like a repair shop type of thing,
where you bring us like a mangled document,
and we just go through with a red pen
and correct all the grammar,
although we will do that.
But we will read you what you have given us.
When you hear someone else,
when you hear the words that you wrote
coming out of someone else's mouth,
it's kind of easier to hear the mistakes.
And then we try to self,
we try to co-correct the errors
in the sentence together,
and we look for patterns
and all the details,
in terms of grammar,
and we fix it together,
rather than just like,
here's a kind of a messed up essay.
Can you please fix this for me?
So we make this more of a learning process,
where we co-edit and co-fix it together.
And even if you don't have any English classes,
and you don't have any English documents,
but you're interested in improving your writing,
just come down,
and we will create an assignment for you.
We'll talk about your situation,
whether you're trying to prepare for TOEIC or GPT,
or you just want to get better at writing.
We can make an assignment for you
and start the process.
So no matter what, there's this.
And I think the Writing Center
is particularly important
because writing in English
is just so much different
than it is in Chinese.
There's no relationship
grammatically, linguistically,
or anything between Chinese and English.
So it's a big jump
to go from Chinese to English.
It's very hard to do it well.
Although I have to say,
I've been impressed
with Changgeng's students' ability to write.
Overall, they're pretty good, yeah.
And let me ask you a question.
When you talk with students like me,
you think that grammar is important
or our pronunciation,
or you think that if you can,
you have the courage
to talk to a foreigner, it's better.
The courage to talk is better.
Most people aren't going to notice,
especially in spoken English,
most people won't know
really notice small grammar errors.
And those can actually,
when you're talking to people,
to non-native speakers,
those can be kind of seen
as local varieties of English,
which are natural.
And even if you were in the United States,
people from Texas talk much different
from people in New York.
There's huge differences,
let alone someone from London,
and someone from London,
and someone from Scotland.
So there's always differences.
There's always accents.
The courage is more important.
The grammar, I guess,
would be something
you'd be more concerned about
in an email.
But as far as speaking goes,
have the courage to speak,
including in class.
Classes tend to go silent
when a teacher asks a question.
And unless we go through the roll call
and choose a name,
there's about zero chance
of a student offering up an answer.
So the courage is needed.
Yeah, pretty.
OK.
And our next question is,
how do you teach your students?
And what method do you recommend
for people who want to learn English?
Well, for me personally,
I like to use environmental awareness
as the main focus of our lessons,
at least for the first half of the semester.
And it's not just talking about
like koala bears or snow leopards
or tigers or elephants.
It's the threats that go with them,
their habitat destruction,
whether it's mountains,
forests,
oceans,
glaciers.
And a glacier is like a being hood,
right?
There's all kinds of problems
or illegal hunting.
All the problems
are always much bigger than that.
Why do these problems exist?
There's a demand for it.
People want status symbols.
People sell it for money.
There's no law enforcement.
The police aren't doing their job.
The government doesn't prioritize this.
There's an international syndicate
where people are shooting
certain birds in Indonesia
and secretly shipping them to China
or tigers being shot in India
secretly shipping them to China.
Why do these people want them?
Traditional Chinese medicine values,
status symbols,
so many elements you end up.
So it's never just about animals or wildlife.
It always encompasses
a very wide range of issues.
So when we're learning
about all these different topics
and just using wildlife
as a basic structure
to get into all kinds of stuff.
And I found that students
are generally very interested
and receptive to this.
And then in the second class
half of the,
after the midterm exam
we'll get into,
we kind of shift gears
and we go into
like modern issues,
well,that's a modern,
wildlife trade is certainly a modern issue,
but like space travel
and the idea of humans
colonizing other planets.
And that might seem unrelated,
but it's actually totally related
because,you know,
maybe we're destroying the earth so fast
that we may have to go
and find a new planet to colonize
because we're ruining this one.
So I actually start to see
the connections between space programs,
space exploration
and the snow leopards
and the elephants.
So it's all connected.
And I think the students can see that.
And in the tests and quizzes,
there's always a couple of essay questions
where I ask them to explain that.
And I can really see
that they have absorbed this,
digested this,
understood this,
synthesized this
and then articulate this in these essays.
And I have to say,
I'm usually very proud of
what the students do on these tests.
And I think it's because
I've chosen a topic which interests them.
Yeah.
So you always use the
environmental protection
or some of the outer space
to be your teaching resources.
That's right.
Yeah.
And as far as resources go,
I, like most teachers, use a textbook.
I use National Geographic's
Reading Explorer 3.
And these topics are all in these chapters.
But I also use a website
called Canvas, canvas.instructure.
And then I make my own weekly PowerPoints
to supplement all of the chapter materials.
And I gather the very current information,
whether in online articles
or YouTube videos
to add to what the textbook has.
So that students can learn quite a lot,I think.
Yeah, that's pretty.
And let me share my way of learning English.
I'm used to reading English books
like Diary of Wimping Kids
before going to bed.
And I also keep a diary
by making use of the words I have just learned
and to make sure that
I firmly memorize those words.
And what do you think about keeping a diary?
Yeah, I think it would be really helpful
to kind of go through those words every day.
We all need to build on our vocabulary.
And keeping a diary maybe is a good idea.
Even for me, it might explain
why my Chinese isn't very good
because I learn words, but I forget them.
I don't write them down.
And I need to do that.
So expanding vocabulary for sure.
Keeping a diary is a great idea.
OK, and our last question.
As we can see,
usually everyone is good at listening
and writing in English.
Except for speaking.
Then how can we improve
our English speaking ability?
You know, I think it well,
Taiwan is not an English environment.
And I think what you said is correct
about the listening and writing.
Because in fact,
I just gave a listening quiz.
And I thought it's pretty challenging and complex.
And students, most of them
did a very good job on it.
They really can understand what I'm saying.
And they rewrote the story.
They reconstructed a short story that I said.
They did a very good job.
I think, you know,
well, first they can join our conversation club.
We also, another,
I forgot to mention another activity
the Language Center offers is movie night.
That's on Tuesday nights.
What I do is, that's from 6 to 8.30.
I will introduce a movie,
tell you why it's culturally significant.
What to look for.
We play it.
Then we have a Q&A session afterwards.
That's another thing they can attend.
And there's another one.
We have starting on Tuesday, April 12th
in a CGUX room in the basement of,
you know, beneath the museum.
This is primarily aimed at juniors and seniors.
But it's open to everyone.
We want to help.
You know, we worry that maybe
because of the lack of speaking
opportunities in English
that maybe students might struggle
with job interviews in English.
So I'm going to have a new,
like a special kind of office hour
from 3 to 5 in that building.
I believe it's that building.
We'll have it on language websites very soon.
And this is for people who want,
who just need practice speaking English
but can't make it to the conversation club.
And they've already completed
all the required courses.
So like we can practice going through your resume.
I will play the role of being an interviewer.
And this is something that I think
can help get students ready
for their job interviews.
Or maybe like if they're applying
for a master's degree program
and have to meet online
with the coordinators of the,
you know, whatever school
they're applying to overseas.
So this is yet another one.
And then finally, I guess I could say,
you know, try to speak up in class
a little bit more.
You know, I've found,
as well as the teachers found,
sometimes our classes are large.
We have 60 students in our class.
And then it's kind of difficult
to get everyone to speak English
in a class like this.
But we try.
You know, we'll break students up
into groups of four.
And I'll try to filter around to,
they have a list of questions,
of structured questions.
I'll try to spend two or three minutes
with each group.
But I found repeatedly
that students will only speak English
if I'm in their group.
But I have to stand up and say,
look, the whole point of this
is that we're all talking in English
at the same time.
Don't wait for me to come to your group
and don't speak Chinese,
Taiwanese or Hakka.
The whole point is
I should hear a lot of English being spoken.
But that doesn't really happen.
So I would just encourage them
to try to, you know,
really do the English activities
when they're in class.
Because I do understand their time,
their opportunities to speak English
are limited.
And this is what they've got.
And I guess one thing you can,
one more idea I have is
when everyone likes to watch movies
and stuff,
I'm sure they use Chinese subtitles
when they're at home or on Netflix.
One thing you can do is
watch a movie the first time
using Chinese subtitles,
the second time using English subtitles
and the third time with no subtitles.
And so you started to learn it in Chinese,
then you went to English
and then see if you can train up
your ear without it.
Because if you were to go to movie theater
in the United States
or any English-speaking country,
there will be no subtitles.
It's not like Taiwan,
like where even when you turn on
the television news,
there's subtitles in Chinese.
I think that's a special culture here.
You got to get used to
not having the subtitles.
So, you know,
with, and I think music can help too.
You know, YouTube,
you know, or you're just,
you know, listening to music
on Spotify or whatever you have.
If you listen to English songs,
the popular culture can help too.
Yeah.
Oh, there's really many ways
to help us to learn English well.
Sure.
Yes.
And honestly,
until now,
I'm still a little bit nervous
when having a conversation with you.
However,
it's really a valuable opportunity
to invite Teacher Gray
to introduce our language center
and share your teaching experience.
Thank you very much for your participation.
It's all my pleasure.
Thanks.
OK.
那今天我们的podcast节目
到这边告一个段落。
那Jojo在这边
想要提醒大家的是
其实我刚跟Teacher Gray的
conversation
都是用很simple的词句。
所以其实对话
没有你们想象中的这么难。
那我们也很欢迎大家
有空的话
可以点我们长庚的语文中心
来看一下
我们到底有什么活动哦。
那今天的podcast
就到这边结束。
谢谢大家。
不管您正在使用哪个平台收听,
请给五星好评。
也别忘了订阅我们的
IG、YouTube频道,
并分享给你的周遭好友。
请搜寻长庚你说,
tellmecgu,
Angela老师听你说,
挺你哦!